Okay, we are now going to call the order, the regular meeting of the Miami City Council for
today's date.
Item 2, the University of Terry Gilbert for 10 years of service, Martian Terry, come on up.
Terry Gilbert was born and raised in Miami, Oklahoma.
He graduated from Miami High School, he graduated from NEO.
He attended OSU where he got a bachelor's in his administration with an emphasis in accounting.
He worked for 13 years at Shangri-La, and their hospitality department and also in accounting.
And he's lived in Martin Barsville, Tulsa, and Dallas, as well.
His father retired as a firefighter for the city of Miami, so he's got that tie as well.
I could just go on and on about Terry.
He's very, I wouldn't want to embarrass him though, he's very pleasant and helpful to the
customers that come in, he's a good team player, he's always letting staff know of training
opportunities and things like that that he needs.
But probably the thing that we appreciate most about Terry at the library is although we have
to call on Michael for networking issues, Terry takes care of all 53 of our computers.
He keeps an updated, he answers our please, day leave when we say help, Terry, my computer's
doing something weird and he'll come in and he didn't have training, he didn't go to school
to do this, he didn't have training in this, he has taught himself by studying and researching
and everything, and so we feel very, very fortunate to have Terry.
He says that he enjoys working at the library, that he has felt like a part of the library and
city of Miami families since the day he started, and he's fulfilled and learning that what he
does, makes the difference in people's lives and it truly does, so.
Terry, you want to say anything?
No, okay.
So, thank you very much, we appreciate all your hard work and thank you very much.
Okay, I remember three is public input on schedule personal parameters, and you want the audience
it wishes to address the council on the agenda item.
There were being nine out of four, as a consent agenda staff is recommending items five through
11 with a consent agenda.
There are no questions on any of those items, so I would entertain a motion, close to the
programmer.
And the second?
Second.
Roll call please?
Johnson.
All right.
Weston.
Forester.
All right.
Lewis.
I think I'm going to have to stay in because there's some nominations on there, I think about it.
Well, I'll do it later.
So, I'll just say.
Okay.
All right.
I am 12. I'm a honorary, honorary, renaming A-Street, Southeast, which is D.V. Owens Boulevard
essential, foreign Holland way, Dean. Well, Ben and I are going to be presenting this
item, but in my case, we've also been doing a lot of good work and we have a kind of a visual
aid to help with. But when we did the last resolution declaring it for a Holland day, there
was a discussion about this segment of street and naming it after firm. And we've talked
about that, but you have businesses addressed. Sometimes when you change an address, you
have folks that may not necessarily want to see that happen. Then what's a good thing to
do, sometimes kind of deteriorates. But in a case like this, and what I've seen in other
cities, is very often they do an honorary name. In other words, the street will not change
its name. You'll still have your address. But yet you put up another street, which identifies
it in honor of the person that you're naming it after. And in this case, we thought that having a street
sign like this and call it Furn Hall in Way would be a very appropriate thing to do. Now, I've
talked with Mike today and what his plans are, if you approve this, is that along that stretch
of street, we probably need to reduce some of the sign in any ways. Probably decades old.
But clean it up at the same time, but then also install the Furn Hall in Way signs at the same
time. So that way, we'll have a fresh look along the entire route. Mike, you might want to turn
around and ensure that he's what we're looking at. And those are the signs that would be up
with your permission. So, as I said, I've seen these in many other cities large and small.
It's a very good way of recognizing people, but yet not necessarily changing people's businesses
addresses or their home addresses. And kind of all of that, I mean, where I'm, I can see what
it says as far as the election's going to be. Or it might be where that is in town.
It's actually going to be the A Street from Steeva, one's Boulevard, to Central. So at each corner
there is where we're going to put them at. And like Dean said, we're going to upgrade the
street signs also to kind of reflect to these and the stop signs and all that. So it's just
a four block stretch there that we're going to, we're going to redo and then name it after
it. Okay, so it has nothing to do with Steve Owens, the naming of Steve Owens, it's just from
Steve Owens. Yes, so Rachel Owens, that helps. Yeah. And also the recognition here is this in front
of the shelter. Right. And also that's the start of the stop point for the annual run
as well. So it'll be something that will be on this part of that too. Yeah. Any questions?
Do we have a motion? I'll make a motion. Okay, in a second. For our colleagues. Lewis, I've
Western. Bye. Forster. Hi. Johnson. Hi.
Sure. Hi. Thanks.
Okay Adam
Okay, you'll be terrific
I think that was a very creative way to honor her and to address the concerns also.
It was a very name of what it is for her.
Adam's like this, make this job fun.
Thank you.
Okay, Adam 13, resolution, proven community financial support and fee waiver to the Oklahoma
for the World War Housing Partners LLC for the demo of structure located at 225F and with east and construction of single-family dwelling at the same.
But do you want me to go here?
Okay, so when we came to you guys a month or so ago and transferred some property.
There were a few properties that were at question that weren't city owned property.
They were owned by somebody else for the Route 66 Landing Project.
One of those properties didn't work out.
And this was a property that we hadn't actually planned to put a house on that was on our demo list.
And Route 66 Landing was going to purchase the property from the owner of the property.
And hold it in case they needed a extra property if one of the other properties felt free.
So that is what happened.
And this has been on the list to be demoted.
It's 225F northeast.
There's actually two structures.
Two houses right next to each other.
225F northeast and 227F northeast that were both on the demo list.
So what we have done with Route 66 Landing is very purchasing the property.
We would like to drive the demo pieces.
The city was going to demo the property anyway.
include this property in what the other properties with label, the permit fees for inspections
and the building permits, the sun fees that you wrote for the other properties.
Chris, you just clarification off. We were talking about this earlier. Also, there's a
stream, the story in it, toward third stream. And that's coming down as well.
Right, so on the 227 property, there's a house that faces F and then there's a little, I haven't
been a little bit, but it looks like maybe a one-bedroom, something or rather that
faces third. That's actually on the 227 property that'll be coming down also.
We had, we also had one of our landlords here in town that is purchased the home across the street
on third that she's going to be doing some remodeling and some work and she had called
and asked about these two properties already in that where they own the list and where we're going to
do something about them. So this all, it works with our plan as far as reading the community of
some properties that need to be taken down. This location here on F, there's a house blue built right
down the street that's part of the same program on a city lot that was owned previously. The city's
actually owned it for years. So it, it all ties in nicely together. And just to be clear, Chris,
this has nothing to do with any flooding or anything like that. No, no, no, no.
Laptated housing that needs to come down. Yes, yes, it's not. I believe this house is one that hasn't
had utility since 2011 and it's just set there for a while. Okay. Now, the end result on this would be
a new house would be built on the lot that is currently 225. We'll have to go through the process
of demolishing 227 in the small house behind it. Then that, since we're, the owner hasn't responded,
we'll have to go through that process and eventually it'll go into a county ownership. If this is one of
those lots that may be for phase two or something, we can get back in our possession. We would hope that
if there's a phase two of this project that we may have another house built on that corner as well. But at the
very least, what we're doing is we're taking out three dilapidated houses and having one brand new house
put there, which is pretty good training. And, Chris, you just to refresh my memory,
I go then the property downtown at their remodeling. How many houses do they have to build and what is
the visit like a square mile or in a mile? All of the locations have to be within a half mile of the
what we're calling the miners exchange building. It's, you know, being the harvest time church
and lots of that in the house too. But all the structures have to be within a half mile of that.
And there'll be 18 silver family.
helps build. That art is one of the, I just wanted to hear that repeated because that's pretty
awesome to what they're doing. Half mile of all down down the 18. And if you want to know
the approximate cost per square foot, I can tell you that now.
Okay, you know thing. Okay, so the action item here is just to prove the resolution.
Okay, the same way, a few way of a resolution that you put before with the addition of
the below fees just for this property. Okay, I will make that motion. Do we have a second?
Okay.
Well, well.
Shult.
Alright.
Question.
I.
Johnson.
All right.
Forster.
Who is? I.
Thanks Christian.
I'm 14. Parting on license agreement with affordable housing partners.
I'll see.
I'll just quickly on this and Christian film and the blinds.
But I've been through these projects before in other cities and you do have these last
minute things that come up. If you remember in the original resolution, we agreed to reserve
36 parking spaces in the parking lot that would be north of this building.
We will identify those parking spaces in a later time.
But that way, they can be assured.
And I think the formula was basically one and a half parking spaces per unit.
That's how we, how we came up with 36.
They have come back to us.
Route 66 landing and said that with their investors and all of that.
They wanted something that kind of showed.
They could show them this says here here's an agreement.
We actually have the ability to have this.
So therefore we came up with this lease agreement.
It was a cooperative agreement between them and us.
And I want to thank Ben very much for putting this together.
One of the nice things about this is that.
It, it, it not only memorializes what the agreement was,
where they will help resurface the entire parking lot as part of this project.
It also identifies that at a later time, they'll participate with us.
What it needs to be resurfaced again.
And finally, they are also indemnifying the city with an insurance policy that we never even
considered asking them for.
So we have some insurance guarantee as well.
But it is a long term agreement.
Originally, I believe they wanted it to be 99 years.
And we didn't agree with that because that's pretty much giving it away.
But as a 20-year agreement that is renewable has responsibilities on both sides,
both their responsibility and our responsibility.
But for there, basically they've indicated that this is something that their investors
and remember they sell the tax credits to be able to do the funding for the modification.
That gives them the comfort level for the closing.
And they're closing tomorrow, basically.
Being a relationship about our attention in the pocket, the effective bank was,
or was it the usual effective date was September 17.
And we've done that to 16 because they believe they could actually be...
running some of those units. This is that this coming February. So there were, so what we're
wanting to do is have this agreement going to place this month. So you want to amend it. Yes,
we want the amended for it's September of 2016. And there's not a schematic included with this.
So it's just 20 or 36 basis. We will probably work with not only them, but the business owners
around that parking lot because one of the things we don't want to, these are going to be kind
of long-term residential. We don't want to take up the spaces for, like the hair salons or the
offices or something. We want those to be convenient for the patrons of those businesses. So probably
it will be more along the middle, a little further north. So be a bit of a walk, but yet they will
know that they have a parking space. If somebody's interested in living in one of these dwellings,
how did they go about that? Is there application there? There will be, and we'll have marketing material,
as they plan to close, they were shooting for tomorrow, but it looks like it'll be Friday on their end.
And then they plan to hit the ground run and we've approved the building, the design plans and
all of that stuff on the miners exchange building and we're in the process of reviewing the
specs and building plans for the houses right now. So we're moving right along the project.
I think one of the last hurdles on the single family homes is they need a variance on some of the
lots at B and A, no B and first street. Right. That are all about the pizza I had expressed,
because it's going to be putting four spaces in there. So they need a little bit more of a little less
of the set back than would be required, and I think that's coming up and I'll tell her. Right. The
lots at on B and first, right behind the middle two homes, there'll be a top part. So there'll be a
designated green space that is taking it part of the lots right there in those in those two spots that
will have some playground equipment for kids that live in those homes right there to be able to have
some green space to play. That's going before the board of adjustments on October 3rd.
So right now have them contact me here and then as we get. Yeah, as we get the information in we'll
make sure that we get that information out to them and we'll have that information with the CVB downtown
in here at the city and on our website. Okay. I think it's a great thing. So we need a motion to
approve of the parking lot, license agreement. Loves to approve. And a second. Roll up.
Please.
Worst in.
Hi.
Worst.
Louis.
I.
Forster.
Hi.
Johnson.
Sure.
Hi.
Thank you.
I'm 15 automatically.
I'm a chief.
How are you?
Hey.
Good.
I would like to upgrade our mutual aid agreement to an automatic aid agreement.
Which will help us in at least three different ways.
One being manpower in this response.
Another being the quick we can get to the northeast part of town with other assistance.
And third of the upper eyes.
Okay.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Did you hear me?
Yeah.
People.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
Can you just do it as a quick description of the difference between mutual and automatic?
If we.
If we request each or that aid.
We have to ask for it.
And so we get to a structure and we know there's a problem.
And then you know you're looking at maybe an additional five minutes to where it fits automatic aid.
As soon as it's confirmed they're called when you're called.
And the time is, you know, it saves you five minutes or so.
So I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
They're going to kind of assess the situation.
Which takes time.
Yeah.
This case.
Oh, we.
We're trying to.
Well, we both do.
Right.
And then we'll only roll on structure fires.
They won't roll.
If we have a arm at the Hampton, you know, it'll be confirmed.
But if we have an incident at Jane informs, you know, they would respond automatically.
Okay.
I'm covering wild land fires.
Wild land?
No.
And it's just for city.
If we need help with.
Wild land would be mutual aid.
Okay.
It's just for structure fires within the city.
And if they need us, they'll have us paged also.
Okay.
I would like to point out when Robert was getting ready to assume the role of chief.
One of the things he set up with running was we had a meeting with ISA.
Because a lot of changes are taking place.
And you want to make sure that whenever we do, does not put our ISA rating at risk.
And I saw them immediately when they talked about an automatic aid agreement.
They said, in every case, we.
We're just a bit more likely to be encouraging.
We absolutely urge it as best for both departments.
It's not only good for the climate departments, it's also good for the, also, good for the
Quarpa Tribalt Department as well.
It's, it's, it's mutually beneficial.
And with what's taking place right now, what Robert is initiating is we're also taking some very
hard looks at what we also have to do related to our ISA rating.
My forward example, 40% of our ISA rating is because of what I want to supply.
the way we handle our water, our fire hydrants, things such as that.
It only makes sense that we can have the best fire department in the world, but if they can't
get water out of a high...
and it doesn't do any good. So he's starting on that as well. A lot of the work that
Robert and Chief Anderson are doing in relationship to our communication system,
5% of our ISO ratings because of our communication system. So we're taking a whole
list of approaches right now. And this is all this will do is it will strengthen our
fire department, will strengthen our police department, and also it ties into a lot of the
work we want to do on our water system as well. So I really want to congratulate
Robert for taking this on and kind of looking at a little broader range of
what's better for not only our department, but their department and
frankly all of our citizens. So I'm very happy with this. Thank you.
Yes. Okay. Do we need a motion to approve?
This is the automatic aid agreement. I'm like a motion. Okay. And I'll second that.
Thank you, Robert.
Four stars.
Hi.
Shult.
Lewis. I. Western.
Hi.
Johnson.
Okay. Resolution for participation with the Oklahoma Department of Transportation in an 80-20
traffic signal match project for Main and Steve Owens Tyler.
Yes, sir. If you guys are going to be back in 2014, we had a resolution for the different
sections for the industry to see if the signal was still warranted. And the term in the ones
that weren't, we removed those signals and it was determined as devils and Main that the signal
was still warranted. So we went back to over that. We said since it's warranted, can we apply
for this federal funding grant through them an 80-20 match that they'll help us put all new
signal in. So we have to have this resolution approved to be in there running for this.
And do we have an idea of the cost yet?
Just from talking to them, they just figured it costs us around $200-250,000. And we've
budgeted it in this year's budget under our grants.
So $200-250 will be the total cost.
Yes, sir.
Sure. It would be 20 percent of whatever that funds.
We're in the 50.
Any questions for Tyler? I know we did talk about this several years ago and we were evaluating all the different
questions and where we still need the lights and the stop signs, et cetera. And this is just a part of that progression of that conversation.
So if there are all the questions, I would make a motion to approve that resolution and ask for a second.
I'll sign.
Four, please.
Shult.
Johnson.
Question.
Four, sir.
All right.
And I'm 17.
Why don't we agreement for ONG?
To bore underneath O'Shell River, Tyler?
Yes, sir. This is about like agreement for ONG.
You said to remove the gas line off the bridge.
I'm like what we do in that water line and go into the park.
I'm so that I'm asking for a lot of agreement to bore in the park and get down.
Okay.
And have you had a chance to get involved with this at all, Ben?
I can remember.
Yeah, because I know we've had the next conversation for a while.
I know this.
new documentation. So you're comfortable with the agreement. Yes, any questions? No. Okay. Do we have a
most to a pretty raw agreement? Most of them. And a second. Go ahead.
All right. Lewis, four of stir. Hi. Western. Hi.
Shut up. Did. He's from Owen G. This is Jared. He is, if he has had any questions. So I think we're
good, Jared. Thank you. Thanks for coming.
Out of 18 campwork construction easement of 1.68 for Oklahoma Department of Transportation,
to complete repairs on Highway 125 Bridge. You'll see the name sausage aboard on this.
Sasha works for a company that's been hired by ODOT to work with all businesses and individuals
that they may need property from. When I have to treat cities just like they treat everybody else.
And as you know, there's going to be redequing the 125 Bridge suddenly starting next year. So they
needed about 1.2 or I believe it's 1.6 acres from us that would be immediately adjacent to the bridge
and the abutments going up to the bridge. So they can store construction equipment and materials and
things such as that. Of course, we want to cooperate with them because this is going to be such a
peppermint. That bridge redec the way it needs to be redec. So this is what this agreement is. I have to treat
us just like everybody else. I do recommend though that we in essence, I think they would be paying
us a minimal amount of money. I think it was about $4,500 if I remember right, Tyler, and I would just
recommend we wave that. Are you talking about the area down right off the bridge? Just the area in
our park area, just as you're approaching the bridge. The way that the front side often is. Yes, they are.
They are going to make sure we remind of them that often and everywhere, well aware of that.
So it's just storing materials and storing equipment during the construction process. We're having long
things and get stuff out quick. We want to believe me. My question, I'm making most of you in
second place. Second. Roll call. Justin. For us. Louis. Hi. Western. Hi. Joe. Hi.
I think did you make in my commotion to weigh them, please? Or is that separate? Actually, one of the
documents in here is for the donation and it's all set up already for it. Okay, so we got you by your vote.
Okay. I'm 19 in college. DQ permit number, long letter number is for construction 1750 in
your feed and 12 inch high density polyethylene, portable water line. Tyler? Yes, we just need to acknowledge
the permit for DQ. This is the city's water line that's on the bridge. We're removing it and
bringing it underneath the river. And so DQ does that.
That's what we had known just at a meeting, the next little meeting is this going to be done
Tyler's about the same time that they're going to be doing the board for the weekend.
Yes, so I was I was I was going to go in to you this morning about that and we're trying to try to coordinate to do so we can do it the same time
He's just let me know when the contractors are going to be ready, but that's what we should go and have to call me of scale and get a good price on it
Yeah, since we're already ready to go
So thank you
Okay, so
There's no need about just three days you'd have in the minute all right. I'm 20 proposed charter changes
If you recall at the last meeting
then go best of not line of
Changes as he would I guess recommend them or things for us to consider and think about and we asked
Just prior this meeting you have kind of reviewed things and if you had any general questions
We would ask Ben that was today the understanding that at our work session next week is when we would really get into the detail
So
Ben is there anything different about the document is before us tonight from what we had last time now
There's nothing different up to this point. I've had very little feedback
Assuming everybody was in the process reviewing it other than
Council member Johnson had talked to me about another alternative
In lieu of paying for the health insurance for the elected officials
Suggestion was made of being able to
Possibly take that
Having an alternative of taking it as a
Credit against your utility bills
Since that point
The United have talked about some other possibilities that would be
With discussion
For instance, there's the possibility of a
Travel stipend
Because each one of you
truly does drive around the city and and
Do things with constituents in response to questions and concerns that they may have
And it's a direct cost to you for
Being a council member that's not otherwise reimbursed
Another
consideration would be a stipend to help cover the cost of cell phones
We I don't believe any of the council members at present have a city cell phone
Now if we were to do that then of course it would be a
Remember that would be published
So that the public could access you, since they would be helping to pay for it.
So those were just some of the possibilities that we were discussing and let me back
up being just gotten the expenses for what the health insurance is and we foresee some of these
other possibilities is being a cheaper expense to the city, but perhaps more meaningful for somebody
that would be serving as a council member.
So other than that, I haven't had any other feedback, so that's what we're here to
discuss this evening.
In our discussions, one of the other thoughts about something like a stipend for vehicle
cost or stipend for a phone, is that that can be applied to a council member equally.
Whereas if you're applying something like a health insurance, different people have different
health insurance plans, or if we're looking at anything related to say a utility bill,
some people's bills are different than others, and it would be kind of different, you
might have some person that would benefit from it more than another council member, that
if it's something like a stipend which relates to your out-of-pocket experience or expenses
by serving the public, it can be applied equally.
Actually, that's very important.
That's really available to us now.
I mean, if we so resired to turn in our mileage, she could be a reimbursed figure to our expenses now.
But I don't know anybody does that, but it's pretty difficult to figure out what your mileage
is when you're driving around the town.
I mean, when you're making a extended trip, that's the LML conference or something.
Sure, that's that.
Yeah.
And since the press is here tonight, I don't want to ask you anything, I want to make sure that the
general public doesn't think that this is all about what can we get as Councilman to the point
of this, as we have some really outdated issues with our charter to need to be corrected.
And so we asked David, when he was here to take a look at that, he did a lot of good work, a lot
of background work, stuff that we were able to read and kind of get a sense of, well, why was
it that way?
And then Ben is coming and kind of taking a look at it with fresh eyes and pointed out, you know,
we've got things where we cite state statute, which was all well and good when that statute
was in effect.
But since Ben repealed, but we still, our charter still says that state statute.
So we've got a lot of up there that you do, and as part of that conversation, I, as an outgoing
council member, said, you know, if you're going to be able to recruit people, you need
They probably need to try to provide some sort of incentive, and so that's where that part
of the conversation comes in, and I'm happy to explore anything along those lines.
I think I had at one time mentioned the health insurance because that's what the school board
you lost, but there are a whole range of things that can be done.
I would just like to see if we could get something before the people in April, I'd like
to see something there that will help with recruitment and retention of future council members.
So, give some more thought to that, but even more importantly, at least deeply, importantly
our elements of the charter that have been as proposals, and if you want to see any changes
there, then next meeting is when we really want to talk about it.
And what I would like to suggest is part of this process, because we've got several months
that we're going to go through, is when I would ask you to sit down with Dean, I would
ask you to sit down with Dean, sit down with Dean, sit down with an e-counseless members, and just talk
about why this is necessary, because we've got to get that information out to the public.
You know, the last thing we wanted people to show up in April and say, well, they just want
health insurance.
So, you know, whatever that we really need to make an effort to communicate why this is important
to our community, and that we, in fact, have some real exposure, which means the citizens
have some exposure, if we don't fix some of these things, or some potential exposure in the future,
and we want to fix something, and it's our job to fix them.
So, that's really what this is about, and again, I would just ask everybody between now and
next week, to take time, to really look through it, and try to come back with some questions
if you're having.
And then, again, I would ask the two of you to make time to visit with Melinda over the next
month or so, and ask the news record to consider, you know, putting some articles out about what
we're doing, and encourage people to come to the meetings.
I don't know if we can print this or not, and a lot of it is references to, you know, the
state statutes, but we need to get information out there about what we're trying to call
publish, and then get people an opportunity to come and comment.
So, are there anything any specifics that anybody wants to get into tonight, and I, other than
what we've already talked about, which is kind of the recruitment, retention, benefits that we would
like to see off everyone in the future?
I've got a couple of questions for Ben, but I can do that on my own, I mean, it's kind of the
basic, you know, I do that on my own, Ben, do you have anything you want to add to anything
tonight?
Well, I think you're synopsis of what's going on here is pretty accurate, and I can just
say that there's a whole lot of the current.
that is very much antiquated. Some of it is contradictory to state law and if we just took the present charter and removed and fixed those particular types of elements we'd have huge gaps in the middle of the thing.
So basically what this does is just rewrites it, puts it in an organized fashion and tries to make it easy to follow and understand.
I would add there was another comment clarifying that the in particular that the city attorney is hired by the city council as opposed to being hired by the city manager.
So that is one other thought that somebody had mentioned to me.
Okay anything else on that item really I was strongly encouraged you to come to next week's meeting.
And talk about issues if you have it.
They look at it perfectly happy with what then is recommending.
We need to get a ride.
Yeah we did.
It's you know it's our constitution.
It's not easy to correct.
I don't want to say they could correct it.
We want to get it right this time around.
Okay if there's nothing else on that item.
Let's see where we are.
Good work.
Do business.
Oh.
Other me business.
Any business to come before the council or dean.
There's none staff reports are in your packet.
Any accounts any announcements?
I've got a question for staff.
How close we are to our own shelter.
We are waiting for furniture fixtures and equipment to come in.
The runs and all of that are being shipped to us now.
Okay.
And once that's done we're ready to go.
I know that our staff has gone through.
We had a punch list and actually a very short punch list which means that everything was put together pretty well.
So as soon as we get the runs and the candles and some of furniture in there I think we'll be talking about a grand opening.
And we'll get good to make.
And we'll see if we can update on our street evaluation.
Actually I had not yet.
Although I understand everything is going well.
Remember that's due on October 31st.
So I believe he's here four days a week.
And I know he's working very closely with Mike and with also with Tyler when it comes to utilities.
Because the utility evaluation is one month after that at the end of that.
So I think everything is going well.
Good.
Do you have anything you'd need to add?
I'm 24.
Too wide, it was very quickly.
Tyler, God, a notification today
that the Mymer Regional Airport has been granted
an airport design grant of 173,880 dollars.
That's for the design for the beacon,
miscellaneous navigational systems,
wind cone, runway and security enhancements,
electronic gate, rehabilitation of the runway lighting,
and install vertical visual guidance system,
which is very important,
because that lets you know you're about to land properly.
This is the first step toward what we hope
is going to be a very much larger grant.
This is about 10% of what the estimated project
can all start.
And a federal grant like this, it's a 90-10 grants,
so we have to cover 10% of the federal government covers 90%.
So, very good work, our very good news,
because this is a design for something
that will really improve our airport
and our airport's viability for other businesses coming into town.
So, I just wanted to do a mouse to that.
You go, Tom, very good job.
And the other one, I send an email to everybody about this,
but I think since Judy's here,
I just wanted to point out that please,
in your calendar at 2 p.m. on the fifth,
and we'll do an event notification
that is going to be Judy's retirement party.
And we'll probably have it in the banquet room
or figuring out how we're going to be doing this,
and I'm still trying to figure out a way
how I can put an ankle bracelet on her and I'll let her go
because I do not want this to be happening.
But Judy is, Judy's earned her retirement.
I think she and I are looking forward to having
a lot of fun in the 90-Distant future.
And she's assured me that every now and then she'll help out
if I need it and I need a lot of help.
So, as I said, this is very bittersweet
because I'm kind of envious of what you have ahead of you,
but also you're going to be missed greatly.
But on top of that, though, I think I notified you
that Amber Purlick is going to be replacing you.
Amber is an internal candidate.
She wants another challenge and believe me,
this is going to be a challenge.
But I've been so impressed with Amber
and what she does with customer service,
our customers every day, she handles
from very difficult situations and does it with great work
and she's really wanting to kind of explore this.
So, during the next couple of weeks, we'll be handing off
Judy's responsibilities with Amber.
Of course, Jill was very upset with me for doing this.
Because now we have to find somebody to replace Amber.
That's all being easy.
Which will not be easy at all, but it's just something
about having good people in a organization
and kind of putting them in places
where they can kind of thrive and explore new opportunities.
So, the only constant in life is change.
So, you'll opt out with your faith at TPM here.
The bank will remember.
I'll be here in the bank, because we expect...
really good crown. In your last day is when? October 5th. No, all kinds of Thursday. Okay. Well,
we, I beg you to stay a couple more days. Okay. Okay. So yeah, we're doing a Thursday. Okay,
begging. Oh, my knees constantly. Okay, well, we will see you on the fifth and in the
20. And that's it. Okay. Thank you. And that leads us, I think, to item 25, which is executive session.
The show at the 25, OS 307 B2. Do we have a most important executive session for the
reasons outline in the agenda item 25? Make a motion. And a second. So, I can roll call, please.
Hi. Western. Hi.
Loist. Hi.
Johnson. Hi.
Shope. Hi.
On there.
Uh, do we want to adjourn or hold up?
Uh, thank you. Yeah. I'm out of executive session. We're out of the
position at 6.55 PM. And we, do we have a most to adjourn? Second.
Roll call. Western.
All right. Loist.
Hi.
Worcester.
Johnson. Hi.
Shope. Hi. And if you want any pie, you need to hurry.
Worcester that.
Biggest hit here.
Welcome.